<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>UQ AIS XNAT</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/</link><description>Recent content on UQ AIS XNAT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installation</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/facility-guides/ctp/installation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/facility-guides/ctp/installation/</guid><description>Installing CTP on Windows 10 CTP installation steps
Create a new user for CTP on UQ RCC XNAT (not an AAF/OpenID user) with required project access, without admin access Download the following files CTP-installer.jar ctp_clinical_site_to_xnat_config.xml dcmtk-3.6.6-win64-dynamic.zip dicom_viewer_Mrbrain.zip Optional if you need more DICOM samples: sample1.zip Install CTP using: cd INSTALL_FOLDER (replace with your actual folder) java -jar CTP-installer.jar Replace CTP/config.xml with ctp_clinical_site_to_xnat_config.xml Edit CTP/config.xml Change &amp;ldquo;xxxx.xxxx&amp;rdquo; in two &amp;ldquo;url&amp;rdquo; tags to &amp;ldquo;xnat.</description></item><item><title>Proxy Server Settings</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/facility-guides/ctp/proxy-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/facility-guides/ctp/proxy-server/</guid><description>If CTP uses a proxy server for internet access, you can update the CTP proxy server settings on Windows as follows
Stop the CTP Windows service
If you already have a Services short-cut on the Windows desktop, double-click the short-cut to start Windows Services If not, click the Windows start button, start typing &amp;ldquo;services&amp;rdquo; and the Services App icon should appear Click the Services App icon to start Windows Services Locate the CTP service in the list of services, right-click and select Stop from the context menu Start the CTP Launcher</description></item><item><title>Windows Service</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/facility-guides/ctp/windows-service/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/facility-guides/ctp/windows-service/</guid><description>The CTP install.bat script uses Apache procrun. Use the following steps to enable CTP as a Windows service, including an update to use a JRE other than system default (leave out step 2 if using the system default JRE)
Install CTP java -jar CTP-installer.jar To use JRE other than system default, edit &amp;lt;ctp-home&amp;gt;/windows/install.bat. Find the &amp;ndash;Jvm=auto, add &amp;ndash;JavaHome entry and set both as follows --JavaHome=&amp;#34;&amp;lt;jre home&amp;gt; &amp;#34; ^ --Jvm=&amp;#34;&amp;lt;jre-home&amp;gt;\bin\server\jvm.dll&amp;#34; ^ ^ is needed to wrap/continue command line in batch file The jvm.</description></item><item><title>Linux Service</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/facility-guides/ctp/linux-service/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/facility-guides/ctp/linux-service/</guid><description>Ubuntu Open ./linux/ctpService-ubuntu.sh. Update the following parameters:
USER=ubuntu CTP_HOME=/opt/ctp/CTP JAVA_BIN=/usr/lib/jvm/java-17-openjdk-amd64/bin JAVA=$JAVA_BIN/java CTP_PID=$CTP_HOME/ctp.pid Run the following to install the ctpService into init.d
sudo ln -s ./linux/ctpService-ubuntu.sh /etc/init.d/ctpService sudo update-rc.d ctpService defaults 98 02 Start and stop CTP using the following commands
sudo service ctpService start sudo service ctpService stop</description></item><item><title>AAF login</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/logging-into-xnat/aaf-login/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/logging-into-xnat/aaf-login/</guid><description>AAF is the recommended way to sign up and login to XNAT.
If your organisation is not in the AAF list during the sign-up process, please contact the respective XNAT support for further options
If your organisation is part of the Australian Access Federation (AAF), you can use your AAF credentials to sign up. Follow the steps below to sign-up/login using AAF.
Open https://xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au Login in with the AAF Single sign-on button (shown below) This will take you to your XNAT home page.</description></item><item><title>Granting Access</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/browsing-xnat/projects/granting-access/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/browsing-xnat/projects/granting-access/</guid><description>Switch to the Access tab. Use Add User or Add Users from List to select the user to add
Select role from
Owners Members Collaborators User roles The following table outlines the permissions given to each role.
Permission Owners Members Collaborators Data - Create ✓ ✓ ✗ Data - Read/Download ✓ ✓ ✓ Data - Update ✓ ✓ ✗ Data - Delete ✓ ✗ ✗ User - Add/Remove ✓ ✗ ✗ User - Change role ✓ ✗ ✗</description></item><item><title>Project anonymiser</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/managing-data/anonymising-data/project-anonymiser/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/managing-data/anonymising-data/project-anonymiser/</guid><description>The Project level anonymiser uses a scripting syntax called DicomEdit to modify, reassign or blank DICOM tags. You can actually use this to create automated workflow for renaming DICOM metadata on datasets
Dicomedit https://wiki.xnat.org/xnat-tools/dicomedit/dicomedit-6-3-language-reference version &amp;#34;6.1&amp;#34; project != &amp;#34;Unassigned&amp;#34; ? (0008,1030) := project (0010,0010) := subject (0010,0020) := session The example in this screenshot basically replicates the behaviour in the HIRF onsite anonymiser for remapping the ReferringPhysicianName, PatientName and PatientID</description></item><item><title>UQ members</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/getting-started/uq-members/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/getting-started/uq-members/</guid><description>Signing into XNAT Step 1 Open https://xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au Note This is the link to the UQ AIS XNAT. If you have been provided with a project specific XNAT link to use, use that one instead Step 2 Login in with the AAF Single sign-on button (shown below).
Follow the AAF login process for your organisation
Step 3 After the AAF sign-in, you should be redirected back to XNAT (Example below)
There will be no projects listed when signing in for the first-time, as your user account would have just been created.</description></item><item><title>Web Upload</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/managing-data/uploading-data/web-upload/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/managing-data/uploading-data/web-upload/</guid><description>Uploading DICOM datasets This is for uploading de-identified DICOM files using the uploader directly from the XNAT website
De-identify DICOM on scanner or upload pc Zip DICOM files into a zip file Login to XNAT (see Login to XNAT) From the top panel, select Upload → Images → Compressed Uploader Specify the following options: Project Destination: Select Prearchive Choose file to select zipped file with DICOMs Click Begin Upload Wait for: Upload percent bar to finish (**percent bar may not appear for small datasets) Background processes panel to appear on bottom right Green tick on under Upload extraction/review for archival In case of Background process errors, expand panel using double arrows on bottom right for more details For further information refer to the XNAT official guide on using the compressed image uploader</description></item><item><title>Other AAF members</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/getting-started/other-aaf-members/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/getting-started/other-aaf-members/</guid><description>This guide is for users from Australian Universities and AAF member organisations, including:
QUT, Griffith, CQU, JCU, USQ, USC CSIRO, Australian Universities AAF VHO accounts Other AAF members usually require UQ AIS XNAT access for:
Management of data acquisition from sites such as CAI, HIRF, TRI Collaborating on projects managed on UQ AIS XNAT Full list of AAF members found here
For all other organisations, use the Non-AAF members guide</description></item><item><title>Resource uploader</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/managing-data/uploading-data/resource-uploader/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/managing-data/uploading-data/resource-uploader/</guid><description>This is to create a web upload form for repeated uploads of any data type.
Navigate to Project → Manage → Project Resource Settings → Start
Select Image Sessions. Enter the following required fields
Title: e.g. Rawdata Resource Folder: e.g. RAW Extract compressed files by default Select Add when complete
To upload file(s) using the resource uploader, Upload Additional Files from the Sessions page</description></item><item><title>Site anonymiser</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/managing-data/anonymising-data/site-anonymiser/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/managing-data/anonymising-data/site-anonymiser/</guid><description>HIRF and CAI data are anonymised on-site by default with the following protocols
Modified Tags DICOM Tag Original value New value PatientBirthDate 10/12/2000 1/1/2000 PatientComments XXXXXXXX Project:Proj001 Subject:TEST_MR Session:TEST_MR-20210405T1220 ReferringPhysicianName Proj001 Proj001 PatientName XXXXXXXX TEST_MR PatientID TEST_MR TEST_MR-20210405T1220 Blanked Tags DICOM Tag AccessionNumber ImageComments OperatorName OtherPatientIDs AdditionalPatientHistory AdmittingDiagnosisDescription MedicalRecordLocator NameOfPhysicianReadingStudy Occupation OtherPatientNames PatientBirthTime PerformingPhysicianName PhysicianOfRecord ReferringPhysicianAddress ReferringPhysicianPhoneNumbers</description></item><item><title>Zip Download</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/managing-data/downloading-data/zip-download/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/managing-data/downloading-data/zip-download/</guid><description>The Project, Subject and Sessions page has the option to Download Images from the right hand side menu
Select Option 2: ZIP download
Note Untick Simply downloaded archive structure to keep scan names in scan folders Filter out the Session and scans from the first two columns and select Submit</description></item><item><title>Alias tokens</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/logging-into-xnat/alias-tokens/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/logging-into-xnat/alias-tokens/</guid><description>AAF is used for logging into the XNAT website itself.
But there are a lot of tools and services that will require a connect to the XNAT server externally
These could include
Windows or Mac desktop clients, like XNAT Desktop Command line tools such as xnatpy, pyxnat, xnatutils etc XSYNC All of these tools and services need a way to authenticating to your XNAT account without AAF.
An alias token is a time-limited, long, randomised username and password used for authenticating from external services, without compromising your AAF account or credentials.</description></item><item><title>Desktop client</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/managing-data/downloading-data/desktop-client/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/managing-data/downloading-data/desktop-client/</guid><description>The XNAT Desktop client is maintained by the XNAT development team. For information see the link below.
XNAT Desktop client https://www.xnat.org/download/desktop-client/ Install client Download and install the client for you operating system
Download images The Project, Subject and Sessions page has the option to Download Images from the right hand side menu
Select Option 1: Download via Desktop Client
Note Untick Simply downloaded archive structure to keep scan names in scan folders Click Download Via App</description></item><item><title>Non-AAF members</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/getting-started/non-aaf-members/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/getting-started/non-aaf-members/</guid><description>This is for users from non-AAF member organisations, including:
QLD Health, TRI, QIMR, QLD Xray Non-AAF members usually require XNAT access for:
Management of data acquisition from sites such as CAI, HIRF, TRI Collaborating on projects managed on UQ-RCC XNAT XNAT uses AAF for login. QCIF/QRIScloud can provide AAF Virtual Home (VHO) accounts for non-AAF users.
Creating an AAF VHO account Step 1 Open a ticket with RCC support to request an AAF account</description></item><item><title>Prearchive</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/managing-data/uploading-data/prearchive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/managing-data/uploading-data/prearchive/</guid><description>If a dataset has not arrived into your XNAT project, the prearchive would be the place to check
This usually happens when:
a DICOM dataset matching an existing session gets resent a part of a session gets uploaded separately Accessing the prearchive Go to Upload on the top menu, and Go to prearchive
The following is an example of a session that is in conflict. We can select the session and choose Details.</description></item><item><title>Scans</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/browsing-xnat/sessions/scans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/browsing-xnat/sessions/scans/</guid><description>The Scans themselves are listed at the bottom with the relevant series descriptions and other information If you hover over one of them, and click the highlighted view details button. This will open up a more details and an image preview window
Here we can also view View DICOM headers
And see the DICOM headers as shown on the right</description></item><item><title>Download Scan</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/managing-data/downloading-data/download-scan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/managing-data/downloading-data/download-scan/</guid><description>Induvidual scans can be downloaded from the Sessions page
Multiple scans can be selected and downloaded using Bulk Actions</description></item><item><title>HIRF users</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/getting-started/hirf-users/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/getting-started/hirf-users/</guid><description>Data acquired at HIRF can be sent to the UQ-RCC XNAT repository
To get started, refer to the relevant guide below:
UQ members UQ Staff and Students Other AAF members QUT, Griffith, CQU, JCU, USQ, USC, Bond CSIRO, QCIF, Australian Universities Full list of AAF members found here Non-AAF members TRI, QIMR QLD Health, QLD Xray, Pacific Radiology If you have multiple valid affiliations, we&amp;rsquo;d recommend using UQ or AAF affiliation where possible If you have any questions, contact rcc-support@uq.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/faq/</guid><description>Example Example Example</description></item><item><title>Search Results</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/search/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>