<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Logging into XNAT on UQ AIS XNAT</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/logging-into-xnat/</link><description>Recent content in Logging into XNAT on UQ AIS XNAT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/logging-into-xnat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AAF login</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/logging-into-xnat/aaf-login/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/logging-into-xnat/aaf-login/</guid><description>AAF is the recommended way to sign up and login to XNAT.
If your organisation is not in the AAF list during the sign-up process, please contact the respective XNAT support for further options
If your organisation is part of the Australian Access Federation (AAF), you can use your AAF credentials to sign up. Follow the steps below to sign-up/login using AAF.
Open https://xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au Login in with the AAF Single sign-on button (shown below) This will take you to your XNAT home page.</description></item><item><title>Alias tokens</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/logging-into-xnat/alias-tokens/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/logging-into-xnat/alias-tokens/</guid><description>AAF is used for logging into the XNAT website itself.
But there are a lot of tools and services that will require a connect to the XNAT server externally
These could include
Windows or Mac desktop clients, like XNAT Desktop Command line tools such as xnatpy, pyxnat, xnatutils etc XSYNC All of these tools and services need a way to authenticating to your XNAT account without AAF.
An alias token is a time-limited, long, randomised username and password used for authenticating from external services, without compromising your AAF account or credentials.</description></item></channel></rss>