<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Getting Started on UQ AIS XNAT</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/getting-started/</link><description>Recent content in Getting Started on UQ AIS XNAT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>UQ members</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/getting-started/uq-members/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/getting-started/uq-members/</guid><description>Signing into XNAT Step 1 Open https://xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au Note This is the link to the UQ AIS XNAT. If you have been provided with a project specific XNAT link to use, use that one instead Step 2 Login in with the AAF Single sign-on button (shown below).
Follow the AAF login process for your organisation
Step 3 After the AAF sign-in, you should be redirected back to XNAT (Example below)
There will be no projects listed when signing in for the first-time, as your user account would have just been created.</description></item><item><title>Other AAF members</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/getting-started/other-aaf-members/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/getting-started/other-aaf-members/</guid><description>This guide is for users from Australian Universities and AAF member organisations, including:
QUT, Griffith, CQU, JCU, USQ, USC CSIRO, Australian Universities AAF VHO accounts Other AAF members usually require UQ AIS XNAT access for:
Management of data acquisition from sites such as CAI, HIRF, TRI Collaborating on projects managed on UQ AIS XNAT Full list of AAF members found here
For all other organisations, use the Non-AAF members guide</description></item><item><title>Non-AAF members</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/getting-started/non-aaf-members/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/getting-started/non-aaf-members/</guid><description>This is for users from non-AAF member organisations, including:
QLD Health, TRI, QIMR, QLD Xray Non-AAF members usually require XNAT access for:
Management of data acquisition from sites such as CAI, HIRF, TRI Collaborating on projects managed on UQ-RCC XNAT XNAT uses AAF for login. QCIF/QRIScloud can provide AAF Virtual Home (VHO) accounts for non-AAF users.
Creating an AAF VHO account Step 1 Open a ticket with RCC support to request an AAF account</description></item><item><title>HIRF users</title><link>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/getting-started/hirf-users/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.xnat.rcc.uq.edu.au/docs/user-guides/getting-started/hirf-users/</guid><description>Data acquired at HIRF can be sent to the UQ-RCC XNAT repository
To get started, refer to the relevant guide below:
UQ members UQ Staff and Students Other AAF members QUT, Griffith, CQU, JCU, USQ, USC, Bond CSIRO, QCIF, Australian Universities Full list of AAF members found here Non-AAF members TRI, QIMR QLD Health, QLD Xray, Pacific Radiology If you have multiple valid affiliations, we&amp;rsquo;d recommend using UQ or AAF affiliation where possible If you have any questions, contact rcc-support@uq.</description></item></channel></rss>